<div>
<p>一旦，我们相梦见，我们是陌生人。我们醒来发现，我们爱着对方.


　　Once we dreamt that we were strangers. We wake up to find that we were dear to each other.</p>
<p>我的心是旷野的鸟，在你的眼睛里找到了它的天空。


　　My heart, the bird of the wilderness, has found its sky in your eyes.</p>
<p>它是大地的泪点，使她的微笑保持着青春不谢。


　　It is the tears of the earth that keep her smiles in bloom.</p>
<p>如果你因失去了太阳而流泪，那么你也失去了群星。


　　If you shed tears when you miss the sun, you also miss the stars.</p>
<p>你看不见你自己，你所看见的只是你的影子。


　　What you are you do not see, what you see is your shadow.</p>
<p>瀑布歌唱道："当我找到了自己的自由时,我找到了我的歌。"


　　The waterfall sing, "I find my song, when I find my freedom."</p>
<p>你微微地笑着，不同我说什么话。而我觉得，为了这个，我已等待得久了。


　　You smiled and talked to me of nothing and I felt that for this I had been waiting long.</p>
<p>人不能在他的历史中表现出他自己，他在历史中奋斗着露出头角。


　　Man does not reveal himself in his history, he struggles up through it.</p>
<p>我们如海鸥之与波涛相遇似地，遇见了，走近了。海鸥飞去，波涛滚滚地流开，我们也分别了。


　　Like the meeting of the seagulls and the waves we meet and come near.The seagulls fly off, the waves roll away and we depart.</p>
<p>当我们是大为谦卑的时候，便是我们最接近伟大的时候。


　　We come nearest to the great when we are great in humility.</p>
<p>决不要害怕刹那－－永恒之声这样唱着。


　　Never be afraid of the moments--thus sings the voice of the everlasting.</p>
<p>"完全"为了对"不全"的爱，把自己装饰得美丽。


　　The perfect decks itself in beauty for the love of the Imperfect.</p>
<p>错误经不起失败，但是真理却不怕失败。


　　Wrong cannot afford defeat but right can.</p>
<p>这寡独的黄昏，幕着雾与雨，我在我的心的孤寂里，感觉到它的叹息。


　　In my solitude of heart I feel the sigh of this widowed evening veiled with mist and rain.</p>
<p>我们把世界看错了，反说它欺骗我们。


　　We read the world wrong and say that it deceives us.</p>
<p>人对他自己建筑起堤防来。


　　Man barricades against himself.</p>
<p>使生如夏花之绚烂，死如秋叶之静美。


　　Let life be beautiful like summer flowers and death like autumn leaves.</p>
<p>我想起了其他的浮泛在生与死与爱以及被遗忘的川流上的的时代，我便感觉到离开尘世的自由了。


　　I think of other ages that floated upon the stream of life and love and death and are forgotten, and I feel the freedom of passing away.</p>
<p>只管走过去，不必逗留着采了花朵来保存，因为一路上花朵自会继续开放的。


　　Do not linger to gather flowers to keep them, but walk on,for flowers will keep themselves blooming all your way.</p>
<p>思想掠过我的心上，如一群野鸭飞过天空。我听见它们鼓翼之声了。


　　Thoughts pass in my mind like flocks of lucks in the sky.I hear the voice of their wings.</p>
<p>"谁如命运似的催着我向前走呢？""那是我自己，在身背后大跨步走着。"


　　Who drives me forward like fate？The Myself striding on my back.</p>
<p>我们的欲望把彩虹的颜色借给那只不过是云雾的人生。


　　Our desire lends the colours of the rainbow to the mere mists and vapours of life.</p>
<p>夏天的飞鸟，飞到我窗前唱歌，又飞去了。 秋天的黄叶，他们没有什麼可唱的，只是叹息一声，飞落在那里。


　　Stray birds of summer come to my window to sing and fly away.　And yellow leaves of autumn, which have no songs, flutter and fall there with a sigh.</p>
<p>伟大的沙漠为了绿叶的爱而燃烧，而她摇摇头、笑著、飞走了。


　　The mighty desert is burning for the love of a blade of grass who shakes her head and laughs and flies away.</p>
<p>跳著舞的流水啊！当你途中的泥沙为你的歌声和流动哀求时， 你可愿意担起他们跛足的重担？


　　The sands in you way beg for your song and your movement,dancing　water.Will you carry the burden of their lameness?</p>
<p>忧愁在我心中沉寂平静，正如黄昏在寂静的林中。


　　Sorrow is hushed into peace in my heart like the evening among the silent trees.</p>
<p>我不能选择那最好的，是那最好的选择我。


　　I cannot choose the best. The best chooses me.</p>
<p>把灯笼背在背上的人，有黑影遮住前路。


　　They throw their shadows before them who carry their lantern on their back.</p>
<p>休息隶属于工作，正如眼睑隶属于眼睛。


　　Rest belongs to the work as the eyelids to the eyes.</p>
<p>群星不会因为像萤火虫而怯於出现。


　　the stars are not afraid to appear like fireflies.</p>
<p>麻雀因孔雀驮著翎尾而替它担忧。


　　The sparrow is sorry for the peacock at the burden of its tail.</p>
<p>瀑布歌唱著：「虽然渴者只需少许水便足够，我却乐意给与我的全部」


　　“I give my whole water in joy,“ sings the waterfall, '' though little of it is enough for the thirsty.''</p>
<p>樵夫的斧头向树要柄，树便给了它。


　　The woodcutter's axe begged for its handle from tree, the tree gave it.</p>
<p>想要行善的人在门外敲著门；爱人的，看见门是敞开的。


　　He who wants to do good knocks at the gate; he who loves finds the gate open.</p>
<p>剑鞘保护剑的锋利，自己却满足於它自己的迟钝。


　　The scabbard is content to be dull when it protects the keenness of the word.</p>
<p>白云谦卑地站在天边，晨光给它披上壮丽的光彩。


　　The cloud stood humbly in a corner of the sky, The morning crowned it with splendour.</p>
<p>尘土承受屈辱，却以鲜花来回报。


　　The dust receives insult and in return offers her flowers.</p>
<p>当富贵利达的人夸说他得到上帝的恩惠时，上帝却羞了。


　　God is ashamed when the prosperous boasts of his special favour.</p>
<p>使卵石臻於完美的，并非锤的打击，而是水的且歌且舞。


　　Not hammer-strokes, but dance of the water sings the pebbles into perfection.</p>
<p>上帝的大能在柔和的微风中，不在狂风暴雨中。


　　God's great power is in the gentle breeze, not in the storm.</p>
<p>采撷花瓣得不著花的美丽。


　　By plucking her petals you do not gather the beauty of the flower.</p>
<p>大的不怕与小的同游，居中的却远避之。


　　The great walks with the small without fear. The middling keeps aloof.</p>
<p>萤火虫对群星说：「学者说你的光有一天会熄灭。」群星不回答它。


　　'' The learned say that your lights will one day be no more.'' said the firefly to the stars.The stars made no answer.</p>
<p>小狗怀疑大宇宙阴谋篡夺它的位置。


　　The pet dog suspects the universe for scheming to take its place.</p>
<p>果实的事业是尊贵的，花的事业是甜美的，但还是让我在默默献身的阴影里做叶的事业吧。


　　Fruit is a noble cause, the cause of flower is sweet, but still let me in the obscurity of the shadow of the dedication to do it cause leaf.</p>
<p>世界上最遥远的距离不是生与死，而是我就站在你面前，你却不知道我爱你


　　The furthest distance in the world，Is not between life and death. But when I stand in front of you，Yet you don't know that I love you.</p>
</div>
