<div>
<p>40句浪漫爱情的经典英语句子</p>
<p>1.我的世界不允许你的消失，不管结局是否完美。</p>
<p>No matter the ending is perfect or not, you cannot disappear from my world.</p>
<p>2.爱情是一个精心设计的谎言</p>
<p>Love is a carefully designed lie.</p>
<p>3.承诺常常很像蝴蝶，美丽的飞盘旋然后不见</p>
<p>Promises are often like the butterfly, which disappear after beautiful hover.</p>
<p>4.凋谢是真实的 盛开只是一种过去</p>
<p>Fading is true while flowering is past</p>
<p>5.为什么幸福总是擦肩而过，偶尔想你的时候…就让…回忆来陪我。</p>
<p>Why I have never catched the happiness? Whenever I want you ,I will be accompanyed by the memory of…</p>
<p>6.爱情…在指缝间承诺 指缝…在爱情下交缠。</p>
<p>Love ,promised between the fingers</p>
<p>Finger rift,twisted in the love</p>
<p>7.如果你为着错过夕阳而哭泣，那么你就要错群星了</p>
<p>If you weeped for the missing sunset,you would miss all the shining stars</p>
<p>8.感受梦的火焰，感觉飞舞瞬间，当一切浪漫遥远，永恒依然</p>
<p>to feel the flame of dreaming and to feel the moment of dancing,when all the romance is far away,the eternity is always there</p>
<p>9.茹菓只遈遇见，吥能停畱，吥茹吥遇见。</p>
<p>If we can only encounter each other rather than stay with each other,then I wish we had never encountered .</p>
<p>10.宁愿笑着流泪，嘢不哭着说后悔 心碎了，还需再补吗？</p>
<p>I would like weeping with the smile rather than repenting with the cry,when my heart is broken ,is it needed to fix?</p>
<p>11.天空没有翅膀的痕迹，而鸟儿已飞过</p>
<p>There are no trails of the wings in the sky, while the birds has flied away.</p>
<p>12.与你保持着一种暖昧的关系，怕自己会爱上你，怕你离开后，我会流泪</p>
<p>When keeping the ambiguity with you ,I fear I will fall in love with you, and I fear I will cry after your leaving.</p>
<p>13.人活着总是要得罪一些人的 就要看那些人是否值得得罪</p>
<p>When alive ,we may probably offend some people.However, we must think about whether they are deserved offended.</p>
<p>14.谁捡走了我的玻璃鞋，寻找遗失的玻璃鞋。</p>
<p>I am looking for the missing glass-shoes who has picked it up</p>
<p>15.命里哊时钟需哊 命里无时莫强求</p>
<p>You will have it if it belongs to you,whereas you don't kveth for it if it doesn't appear in your life.</p>
<p>16.没有谁对不起谁，只有谁不懂得珍惜谁。</p>
<p>No one indebted for others,while many people don't know how to cherish others.</p>
<p>17.永远不是一种距离，而是一种决定。</p>
<p>Eternity is not a distance but a decision.</p>
<p>18.在回忆里继续梦幻不如在地狱里等待天堂</p>
<p>Dreaming in the memory is not as good as waiting for the paradise in the hell</p>
<p>19.哪里有真爱存在，哪里就有奇迹。</p>
<p>Where there is great love, there are always miracles.</p>
<p>20、爱情就像一只蝴蝶，它喜欢飞到哪里，就把欢乐带到哪里。</p>
<p>Love is like a butterfly. It goes where it pleases and it pleases where it goes.</p>
<p>21.假如每次想起你我都会得到一朵鲜花，那么我将永远在花丛中徜徉。</p>
<p>If I had a single flower for every time I think about you, I could walk forever in my garden.</p>
<p>22.有了你，我迷失了自我。失去你，我多么希望自己再度迷失。</p>
<p>Within you I lose myself, without you I find myself wanting to be lost again.</p>
<p>23.每一个沐浴在爱河中的人都是诗人。</p>
<p>At the touch of love everyone becomes a poet.</p>
<p>24.Look into my eyes - you will see what you mean to me.</p>
<p>看看我的眼睛，你会发现你对我而言意味着什么。</p>
<p>25.Distance makes the hearts grow fonder.</p>
<p>距离使两颗心靠得更近。</p>
<p>26.I need him like I need the air to breathe.</p>
<p>我需要他，正如我需要呼吸空气。</p>
<p>27.If equal affection cannot be, let the more loving be me.</p>
<p>如果没有相等的爱，那就让我爱多一些吧。</p>
<p>28.Love is a vine that grows into our hearts.</p>
<p>爱是长在我们心里的藤蔓。</p>
<p>29.If I know what love is, it is because of you.</p>
<p>因为你，我懂得了爱。</p>
<p>30.Love is the greatest refreshment in life.</p>
<p>爱情是生活最好的提神剂。</p>
<p>31.Love never dies.</p>
<p>爱情永不死。</p>
<p>32.The darkness is no darkness with thee.</p>
<p>有了你，黑暗不再是黑暗。</p>
<p>33.We cease loving ourselves if no one loves us.</p>
<p>如果没有人爱我们，我们也就不会再爱自己了。</p>
<p>34.There is no remedy for love but to love more.</p>
<p>治疗爱的创伤唯有加倍地去爱。</p>
<p>35.When love is not madness, it is not love.</p>
<p>如果爱不疯狂就不是爱了。</p>
<p>36.A heart that loves is always young.</p>
<p>有爱的心永远年轻。</p>
<p>37.Love is blind.</p>
<p>爱情是盲目的。</p>
<p>38.Love is like the moon, when it does not increase, it decreases.</p>
<p>爱情就像月亮，不增则减。</p>
<p>39.The soul cannot live without love.</p>
<p>灵魂不能没有爱而存在。</p>
<p>40.Brief is life, but love is long.</p>
<p>生命虽短，爱却绵长。</p>
</div>
