<div>
<p>Not Just a Mom</p>
<p>母亲的含义</p>
<p>A woman named Emily renewing her driver's license at the County Clerk's office was asked by the woman recorder to state her occupation. She hesitated, uncertain how to classify herself. "What I mean is," explained the recorder, "do you have a job, or are you just a ... "</p>
<p>一位名叫埃米莉的妇女在县办事处给驾驶执照续期时，一名女记录员问及她的职业。她犹豫了一下，不敢肯定应如何将自己归类。“我意思是说你有没有工作，”那名记录员解释说，“还是说你只不过是一名……”</p>
<p>"Of course I have a job," snapped Emily. "I'm a mother."</p>
<p>“我当然有工作，”埃米莉马上回答，“我是一名母亲。”</p>
<p>"We don't list 'mother' as an occupation ... 'Housewife' covers it," said the recorder emphatically.</p>
<p>“我们这里不把‘母亲’看成是一个职业……‘家庭主妇’就可以了。”那名记录员断然回答。</p>
<p>I forgot all about her story until one day I found myself in the same situation, this time at our own Town Hall. The Clerk was obviously a career woman, poised, efficient, and possessed of a high sounding title like, "Official Interrogator" or "Town Registrar." "What is your occupation?" she probed.</p>
<p>这个故事听后，我就忘了。直到有一天在市政厅，我也遇到了同样的情况。很显然，那名办事员是位职业女性，自信、有能力，并有着一个类似“官方讯问员”或“镇登记员”之类很堂皇的头衔。“你的职业？”她问道。</p>
<p>What made me say it, I do not know ... The words simply popped out. "I'm a Research Associate in the field of Child Development and Human Relations."</p>
<p>至今我也不知道，当时是什么因素作怪，我脱口而出：“我是儿童发育和人类关系研究员。”</p>
<p>The clerk paused, ballpoint pen frozen in midair, and looked up as though she had not heard right.</p>
<p>那名办事员愣住了，拿着原珠笔的手也不动了。她抬头看着我，好像没有听清楚我说什么似的。</p>
<p>I repeated the title slowly, emphasizing the most significant words. Then I stared with wonder as my pronouncement was written in bold, black ink on the official questionnaire.</p>
<p>我慢慢地把我的职业再重复一遍，在说到重要的词时还加重语气。然后，我惊奇地看着我的话被粗黑的笔记录在官方的问卷上。</p>
<p>"Might I ask," said the clerk with new interest, "just what you do in your field?"</p>
<p>“我能不能问一下，”这名办事员好奇地问，“你在这个领域具体做什么？”</p>
<p>Coolly, without any trace of fluster in my voice, I heard myself reply, "I have a continuing program of research, (what mother doesn't), in the laboratory and in the field, (normally I would have said indoors and out). I'm working for my Masters, (the whole darned family), and already have four credits, (all daughters). Of course, the job is one of the most demanding in the humanities, (any mother care to disagree?) and I often work 14 hours a day, (24 is more like it). But the job is more challenging than most run-of-the-mill careers and the rewards are more of a satisfaction rather than just money."</p>
<p>我非常镇定地答道：“我有一个不间断的研究项目（哪位母亲不是这样呢？），工作地点包括实验室和现场（通常我会说室内和户外）。我在为我的学位努力（就是我们一家人），而且已经有了四个学分（全部是女儿）。当然，我的工作是人类要求最高的工作之一（有哪位母亲会反对吗？）我通常工作一天14小时（24小时更为准确）。但这项工作比大部分普通工作都具有挑战性，而它通常带来的回报不是金钱，更多的是满足感。”</p>
<p>There was an increasing note of respect in the clerk's voice as she completed the form, stood up, and personally ushered me to the door.</p>
<p>那名办事员在填完表格后，站起来，亲自把我送到门口。在这个过程中，她说话时流露出一股敬意。</p>
<p>As I drove into our driveway, buoyed up by my glamorous new career, I was greeted by my lab assistants - ages 13, 7, and 3. Upstairs I could hear our new experimental model, (a 6 month old baby), in the child-development program, testing out a new vocal pattern.</p>
<p>我回到家，把车停在家门前的车道时，还对自己响亮的头衔觉得飘飘然。我那三名年龄分别为13岁、7岁、3岁的实验室助手正在等着我，从楼上传来我们的新实验模特儿（六个月大的婴儿）的声音，她正放开嗓门，测试着新的声音模式。</p>
<p>I felt triumphant! I had scored a beat on bureaucracy! And I had gone on the official records as someone more distinguished and indispensable to mankind than "just another mother."</p>
<p>我感到欢欣鼓舞！我竟然打败了官僚机构！如今，在官方的纪录上，我成了人类超群出众、不可或缺的人物，而不仅仅是一位母亲。</p>
<p>Motherhood ... What a glorious career! Especially when there's a title on the door.</p>
<p>母亲……这是多么光荣的职业啊！特别是现在这已经成为官方记录了。</p>
<p>Does this make grandmothers "Senior Research Associates in the field of Child Development and Human Relations" and great grandmothers "Executive Senior Research Associates"? I think so!!!</p>
<p>这是不是说奶奶和姥姥就是“资深儿童发育和人类关系研究员”，而曾祖母则是“高级研究员”呢？我想是这样的！</p>
<p>I also think it makes Aunts "Associate Research Assistants".</p>
<p>我想，小姨子也因此成了“研究员助理”。</p>
</div>
