<div>
<p>Try to Remember the Good Things</p>
<p>多想想美好的事情</p>
<p>When times become difficult (and you know they sometimes will), remember a moment in your life that was filled with joy and happiness.</p>
<p>当你身陷困境的时候（你有时会），回想你生命中快乐和幸福的时刻。</p>
<p>Remember how it made you feel, and you will have the strength you need to get through any trial.</p>
<p>回想它是如何使你快乐，你便有了走出困境的勇气。</p>
<p>When life throws you one more obstacle than you think you can handle, remember something you achieved through perseverance and by struggling to the end.</p>
<p>当面对重重困难，你感觉举步维艰的时候，回想你以前是如何坚持到底战胜困难的最后时刻的。</p>
<p>In doing so, you'll find you have the ability to overcome each obstacle brought your way.</p>
<p>这样，你就会发现你有能力克服每个障碍。</p>
<p>When you find yourself drained and depleted of energy, remember to find a place of sanctuary and rest.</p>
<p>当你觉得精疲力尽的时候，暂时离开，让自己稍作休息。</p>
<p>Take the neccessary time in your own life to dream your dreams and renew your energy, so you'll be ready to face each new day.</p>
<p>给自己留点时间做做梦，充一下电，这样你就能以崭新的面貌去面对每一天。</p>
<p>When you feel tension building, find something fun to do. You'll find that the stress you feel will dissipate and your thoughts will become clearer.</p>
<p>当你感觉到紧张的压力，做一些有乐趣的事吧。你会发现压力在渐渐消逝，你的想法也渐渐明朗了。</p>
<p>When you're faced with so many negative and draining situations, realize how minuscule problems will seem when you view your life as a whole--and remember the positive things.</p>
<p>当你面对重重困难的时候，要意识到相对于你的整个生命，这些难题其实是微不足道的－－铭记你生命中美好的东西。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ （分专题阅读）</p>
<p>☆ （精华博览版）</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ 特荐：</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>中外名家文集 尽赏大家风采！</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>中外名作博览 精彩美文集锦！</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
