<div>
<p>In life we are happiest when...</p>
<p>生活中我们最幸福</p>
<p>A man and his girlfriend were married. It was a large celebration.</p>
<p>一个男人和他的女朋友结婚，举行了一场盛大的结婚庆典。</p>
<p>All of their friends and family came to see the lovely ceremony and to partake of the festivities and celebrations. All had a wonderful time.</p>
<p>所有的朋友和家人都来到结婚典礼上参加欢宴和庆祝活动。大家都过得很开心。</p>
<p>The bride was gorgeous in her white wedding gown and the groom was very dashing in his black tuxedo. Everyone could tell that the love they had for each other was true.</p>
<p>穿着白色婚纱的新娘漂亮迷人，穿着黑色礼服的新郎英俊潇洒。每个人都能看出他们彼此的爱是真诚的。</p>
<p>A few months later, the wife came to the husband with a proposal, "I read in a magazine, a while ago, about how we can strengthen our marriage," she offered. "Each of us will write a list of the things that we find a bit annoying with the other person. Then, we can talk about how we can fix them together and make our lives happier together."</p>
<p>几个月后，妻子走近丈夫提议说：“我刚才在杂志上看到一篇文章，说的是怎样巩固婚姻。”她说：“我们两个人都各自把对方的小毛病列在一张纸上，然后我们商量一下怎样解决，以便使我们的生活更幸福。”</p>
<p>The husband agreed. So each of them went to a separate room in the house and thought of the things that annoyed them about the other. They thought about this question for the rest of the day and wrote down what they came up with.</p>
<p>丈夫同意了。于是他们各自走向不同的房间去想对方的缺点。那一天余下的时间里，他们都在思考这个问题，并且把他们想到的都写下来。</p>
<p>The next morning, at the breakfast table, they decided that they would go over their lists</p>
<p>第二天早上，吃早饭的时候，他们决定谈谈彼此的缺点。</p>
<p>"I'll start," offered the wife. She took out her list. It had many items on it, enough to fill 3 pages. In fact, as she started reading the list of the little annoyances, she noticed that tears were starting to appear in her husband's eyes.</p>
<p>“我先开始吧。”妻子说。她拿出她的单子，上面列举了很多条，事实上，足足写满了三页。当她开始念的时候，她注意到丈夫眼里含着泪花。</p>
<p>"What's wrong?" she asked. "Nothing," the husband replied, "keep reading your list."</p>
<p>“怎么啦?”她问。“没什么，”丈夫答道，“继续念吧。”</p>
<p>The wife continued to read until she had read all three pages to her husband. She neatly placed her list on the table and folded her hands over the top of it.</p>
<p>妻子又接着念。整整三页都念完之后她把单子整齐地放在桌上，两手交叉放在上面。</p>
<p>"Now, you read your list and then we'll talk about the things on both of our lists," she said happily.</p>
<p>“现在该你念了，然后我们谈谈所列举的缺点。”她高兴地说。</p>
<p>Quietly the husband stated, "I don't have anything on my list. I think that you are perfect the way that you are. I don't want you to change anything for me. You are lovely and wonderful and I wouldn't want to try and change anything about you."</p>
<p>丈夫平静地说：“我什么也没写，我觉得像你这样就很完美了，我不想让你为我改变什么。你很可爱迷人，我不想让你改变。”</p>
<p>The wife, touched by his honesty and the depth of his love for her and his acceptance of her, turned her head and wept.</p>
<p>妻子被丈夫的诚实和对她深深的爱和接纳感动了，她转过头去哭起来。</p>
<p>In life, there are enough times when we are disappointed, depressed and annoyed. We don't really have to go looking for them. We have a wonderful world that is full of beauty, light and promise. Why waste time in this world looking for the bad, disappointing or annoying when we can look around us, and see the wondrous things before us?</p>
<p>生命中我们有很多的失望、沮丧和烦恼，我们根本不需要寻找。我们美妙的世界充满了美丽、光明、希望。但是，当我们放眼四周时，为什么浪费时间寻找不快、失望和烦恼，而看不到我们面前的美好事物呢？</p>
</div>
