<div>
<p>Clouds had settled in on the frigid day.


　　Their love was frozen, held in place.


　　His loving stares and her fair love


　　Could not conquer their stubborness.


　　No matter how hard she tried she was ridiculed.


　　All the signs he had shown with great care


　　Were not perceived by other than her.</p>
<p>在寒冷刺骨的这天，密云涌动。


　　他们的爱犹如被冰封，停滞不前。


　　他深情的凝视和她纯真的爱，


　　都无法打破彼此间的顽固屏障。


　　无论她多努力，都免不了旁人的奚落。


　　他小心翼翼传递的所有爱的暗示，


　　除了她，别人都不以为意。</p>
<p>He had loved her for quite some time,


　　And she well knew what he wanted.


　　But how was she to speak up?


　　How was he to get past his reputation to love her for real?


　　She tried so hard to get past the stares


　　Past the rumors and humored lies


　　And he saw so well past and tried hard as well.</p>
<p>他对她的爱已非一朝一夕，


　　而她也清楚他所渴望得到的


　　但是她要如何说出口？


　　他要如何放下身份，真心真意地爱她？


　　她竭力忽视他的深情凝望，


　　忽视流言蜚语，以及甜蜜的谎言，


　　而他也非常努力，成功抵挡住这一切。</p>
<p>Like Romeo and Juliet they had moments.


　　Silent and unknown moments where their eyes met,


　　Hearts raced, and it was like love at first sight.


　　But ala it just could not come through.


　　Like Jack and Sally he could not see


　　All she had done, all she sacrificed for him.


　　Suffering and tattered her heart was when he would not look astray his work


　　To catch a glimpse of the girl behind him,


　　Darkness covered in her golden hair.


　　Their personalities mixed and mingled,


　　His status as a social king and she as a Fallen Angel


　　Went so well with everything.


　　And who was this girl you may ask? The Night of his Day?


　　None other than me, who stands before you now.


　　Cloaked in darkness and despair, waiting for the chance to show her love.


　　Maybe today, maybe tomorrow. Uncertain she was standing in the shadows.


　　Whether or not they do fall deep in love, well now, it's just not that fair to know.


　　Patient and innocent they shall wait; nothing else to do but wait.</p>
<p>就像罗密欧和朱丽叶，他们曾拥有美妙时刻。


　　那些静谧的无名时刻，他们四目相投，


　　心如鹿撞，犹如一见情花开。


　　奈何啊，这段恋情只开花不能结果。


　　就像杰克和莎莉，他看不到，


　　她所做的一切，为他所做的牺牲。


　　她备受煎熬，心渐渐破碎，只因他心无旁骛，寄情工作，


　　也不看一眼他身后的那个女孩。


　　黑暗笼罩着她金色的头发。


　　他们个性相投相容，


　　他在社交界如鱼得水，而她则是“堕落天使”


　　一切都那么美好。


　　你也许会问，这位姑娘是谁？他是白昼而她是黑夜？


　　那就是我，正站在你面前的这位姑娘。


　　她被阴暗和绝望缠绕，等待着示爱的机会。


　　可能今天，可能明天。她站在暗处，犹豫不定。


　　他们是否深坠爱河，现在，仍说不清道不明。


　　他们要耐着性子，单纯天真地等待时机；什么也做不了，只能等待。</p>
</div>
