<div>
<p>The sun is just rising in the morning of another day. What can I wish that this day may bring me? Nothing that shall make the world or others poorer, nothing at the expense of other men; but just those few things which in their coming do not stop me but touch me rather, as they pass and gather strength.</p>
<p>朝阳又在新的一天中冉冉升起。我期许这一天带给我什么呢？我希望带给我的不是令世界或他人更贫穷的东西，不是损害别人的东西，而是那些微小的、能触动我的东西，它们经过时，或者不断聚集力量之时不会妨碍我。</p>
<p>I wish that this day could bring me a few friends, who understand me, and yet remain my friends; I also wish that this day could bring me a work to do which has real value.</p>
<p>我希望这一天能够带给我一些惺惺相惜的朋友，希望我们友谊长存；我也希望这一天能够给我带来一份真正有价值的工作。</p>
<p>I wish that this day could bring me a mind unafraid to travel, even though the trail be not blazed, and I wish that this day could bring me an understanding heart.</p>
<p>我希望这一天能够带给我无畏远行的胸怀，即使旅途没有光亮的照耀；我还希望这一天能够带给我善解人意的心。</p>
<p>I wish that this day could bring me a sight of the eternal hills, and the blue sea stretching to the horizon, and of something beautiful which the hands of men have made.</p>
<p>我希望这一天能够让我看到永恒的山冈，看到辽阔无边的蓝色海洋，看到人类的双手造就的美丽事物。</p>
<p>I wish that this day could bring me a sense of humor, and the power to laugh, a little leisure with nothing to do.</p>
<p>我希望这一天能够带给我幽默感，笑的力量和无事可做的片刻悠闲。</p>
<p>And I crave for a few moments of quiet, silent meditation in the morning of this day.</p>
<p>这一天的早上，我渴望片刻安静的沉思静想。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ （分专题阅读）</p>
<p>☆ （精华博览版）</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ 特荐：</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>中外名家文集 尽赏大家风采！</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>☆  ☆</p>
<p>中外名作博览 精彩美文集锦！</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
