<div>
<p>A number of years ago, I had the rather unique experience of being backstage in Madison Square Garden, in New York, during the Ringling Brothers Barnum &amp; Bailey Circus. To say the least, it was a fascinating experience. I was able to walk around looking at the lion tiger giraffes and all the other circus animals. As I was passing the elephant I suddenly stopped, confused by the fact that these huge creatures were being held by only a small rope tied to their front leg. No chain no cages. It was obvious that the elephants could, at any time, break away from their bonds but for some reason, they did not. I saw a trainer near by and asked why these beautiful, magnificent animals just stood there and made no attempt to get away.</p>
<p>多年前，在纽约的麦迪逊广场花园里，我走进了林林兄弟与巴纳姆贝利马戏团，拥有了一次相当独特的幕后经历。至少可以这样说，那是一次迷人的经历。我可以四处走动，看看狮子、老虎、长颈鹿和其他所有的马戏团动物。当我走过那群大象时，我突然停了下来。这些庞然大物只是被一根小绳绑着它们的前肢，这事让我困惑不已。没有链条，没有笼子。显然，那群大象随时都能挣脱这种束缚，然而出于某种原因，它们并没有这样做。我看见附近有一位驯兽师，于是问他为何这些美丽的庞然大物只是站在那儿，一点也没有要逃跑的意图。</p>
<p>“Well,” he said, “when they are very young and much smaller we use the same size rope to tie them and, at that age, it's enough to hold them. As they grow up, they are conditioned to believe they cannot break away. They think the rope can still hold them, so they never try to break free.”</p>
<p>“噢，”他说道，“当它们还很年幼且个头比现在小得多的时候，我们就用同样大小的绳子绑住它们。在那个年龄，这样的绳子足以拴住它们。而随着年月增长，它们出于惯性而深信自己无法逃跑，仍然认为那根绳子能够拴住它们，于是便不再试图挣脱了。”</p>
<p>I was amazed. These animals could at any time break free from their bonds but because they believed they could not, they were stuck right where they were.</p>
<p>我很是惊讶。这些动物随时都能挣脱他们身上的束缚，但却因为它们相信自己没有那个能力，结果让自己一直受困其中。</p>
<p>Like the elephant how many of us go through life hanging onto a belief that we cannot do something, simply because we failed at it once before? How many of us are being held back by old, outdated beliefs that no longer serve us? Have you avoided trying something new because of a limiting belief? Worse, how many of us are being held back by someone else's limiting beliefs? Do you tell yourself you can't sell because you're not a salesperson?</p>
<p>我们中有多少人何尝不像这些大象那样一辈子将自己禁锢于一种认为自己做不到的信念，而仅仅因为我们曾经失败过？我们中又有多少人被那些陈旧过时、不再对我们有所帮助的信念所阻拦？你是否曾经因为一种自我束缚的观念而避免尝试一些新事物？更糟的是，我们中有多少人因为他人的狭隘观念而固步自封？你是不是告诉过自己你无法推销因为你不是个天生的推销员？</p>
<p>Particularly in starting or running a busines we are cautioned not to take risk usually by well intentioned friends and family. How many of us have heard, “You can't do that”? These are the dream stealers who, due to their own limiting belief will attempt to discourage you from living your dreams. You must ignore them at all cost! I am not suggesting that you should not seek advice from qualified individuals and mentor but that you avoid like the plague being swayed by the limiting beliefs of other especially people who are not in their own business.</p>
<p>尤其是在创业初始或是经营某项生意时，我们会被警告不要冒险，而这些警告通常来自我们那些出于好意的朋友和家人。我们中有多少人曾经听到过诸如“你不能那样做”的话？这些都是偷走梦想的人，他们出于个人的狭隘观念，会试图打击你实现梦想的壮志。你必须不惜任何代价来忽视他们！我并非说不去咨询请教于那些够资格给你意见的人或导师，但你就该像躲避瘟疫似地避免被那些想法局限的人所动摇，特别是那些并非自己创业营商的人。</p>
<p>Challenge your own limiting beliefs by questioning them. If you begin to question a belief, you automatically weaken it. The more you question your limiting belief the more they are weakened. It's like kicking the legs out from under a stool. Once you weaken one leg, the stool begins to lose its balance and fall. Think back to a time when you “sold” someone on yourself. We are selling all the time. You have to sell your ideas to your spouse, your children, and your employees—even your banker. Maybe, as a child, you sold Girl Scout cookies or magazine subscriptions to raise money for your school team. That was selling too!</p>
<p>对那些自我束缚的想法提出质疑，挑战那些观念。当你开始质疑一种观念时，你就是在开始削弱其力量。你越是质疑那些狭隘的观念，就越能削弱其力量。这就像踢掉凳子下面的凳腿。一旦你踢松了其中一条凳腿，整张凳子就开始失去平衡，接而倒塌。回想一下从前你是怎样独自向某人“推销”一些东西的。我们无时不在推销。你得把自己的想法推销给你的另一半、你的孩子和你的雇员……甚至是你的银行经理。也许，在孩童时期，你卖过女童子军饼干或是推销过杂志订阅，以此来为你的校队筹集资金。那也是一种推销！</p>
<p>Once you realize you are, in fact, a capable salesperson, you have weakened that old belief and begun to replace it with a new, empowering one. Look for references to support the new beliefs you want to cultivate. As in the example of the stool, you want to reinforce your beliefs by adding more and more “legs” to them. Find people who have accomplished what you want to accomplish, discover what they did and model their behavior. Remember back to times in your past when you were successful and use that experience to propel yourself forward. If your challenge is in sale read sales books and listen to tapes or attend sales seminars. This is a critical area of your busines one that cannot be undermined by limiting beliefs.</p>
<p>一旦你意识到自己其实是个能干的推销员，你就已经削弱了那种陈旧的观念，而开始以一种崭新且使你充满力量的观念取而代之。查找相关的资料来支撑你想培养的新观念。就像那凳子的比喻，你想加强你的新观念，那你就给它添加更多的“腿”。寻找那些已经达成你心中目标的人，发掘他们过去的做法，并且模仿他们的行为。回想那些你曾经获得成功的时光，并以那些经历来鼓舞自己前进。如果你的难题在于销售，就阅读有关推销的书籍，听听有关销售的磁带资料，或是参加一些推销研讨会。这是你事业的关键领域，是不能被那些局限的观念所破坏的。</p>
<p>There is a technique called “fake it until you make it” that works well. I am not suggesting you live in denial, just that you begin to see yourself succeeding. Visualize your successes. See yourself vividly in your mind's eye making the sale and reaching your goals. Affirm, over and over, that you are succeeding.</p>
<p>有一种叫作“先假装，后实现”的技巧，效果很好。我并不是在建议你自欺欺人地生活，只是想让你从一开始就假想自己在迈向成功，想象自己的成功。在头脑里逼真地想象自己在推销，达成目标。一次次地确认自己正迈向成功。</p>
<p>Write your affirmations daily. Of course, make sure that you take the appropriate actions. As it says in the Bible, “Faith without works is dead.”</p>
<p>每天自我肯定一番。当然，得确保自己采取了恰当的行动。正如《圣经》里所说的：“没有付诸实践的信念是死的。”</p>
<p>Remember that your subconscious mind does not know the difference between real and imaginary. Before you go on a sales call, take a moment and mentally rehearse the scene, just like actors and athletes do. Tell yourself, “I'm a great salesperson.” Do this over and over, especially just before a sales call. See the sale being made. See and feel the success. You will be pleasantly amazed at the result. Don't take my word for it. Give it a try. You have nothing to lose and everything to gain.</p>
<p>记住，你的潜意识并不清楚真实和幻想之间的差别。在你要打一通推销电话前，花一点时间在脑海里预演一下那情景，就像演员和运动员所做的那般。告诉你自己：“我是个伟大的推销员。”反复地这样做，特别是在打一通推销电话前的片刻。幻想在进行推销，幻想成功，感受成功。你将会为其结果感到惊讶和欣喜。别光听我说，你去试试。你不会有任何损失，却会收获一切。</p>
<p>It has been said throughout history that whatever you believe with conviction, you can achieve. Don't be like the poor elephant and go through your life stuck because of a limiting belief you were given or developed years ago. Take charge of your life and live it to the fullest. You deserve the best!</p>
<p>从古至今，人们一直都在说，只要你深信不疑，就能达成所愿。别像那只可怜的大象，一辈子受困于一种多年前别人给予你的狭隘观念，又或是多年前养成的桎梏信念。掌控你的人生，充分地把握每分每秒。你值得拥有最棒的人生！</p>
</div>
