<div>
<p>如何种植幸福（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>Step one:</p>
<p>Plant yourself deep in a bed of faith, and pack it down solid and tight. Drench daily with positive thinking, and keep saturated just right. Mulch often with　forgivenss, for this will help you grow. Quickly remove any seeds of worry, for they will soon germinate, and keep out the weeds of despair. Nourish disappointments with hope whenever it is neeeded, and always stay cool and shaded when you feel irritated or heated. Trim away guilt or depression, for they create decay, and cultivate with happy memories as often as every day.</p>
<p>步骤一：</p>
<p>把自己紧紧牢牢地埋在“信念”的土壤里。每天浇灌以“积极”的思想，并始终保持湿润。经常以“宽容”来护根，这样有利于幸福的幼苗成长。一旦发现忧虑的种子，及时除掉，否则它们很快就生根发芽，同时也将绝望消灭在萌芽状态。在必要时，用希望来滋养失望；烦躁不安的时候，保持冷静。修剪枝叶，修剪去愧疚和沮丧，否则很快出现衰枝败叶。每天用“幸福回忆”细心照料幼苗。</p>
<p>Step two:</p>
<p>Harvest the lessons of the past; just dig, pick, and hoe. And nurture the roots of the present, for now is when you flourish and grow. Start planting for the future; set your goals in a row. Spade the bed well for all your dreams to grow.</p>
<p>步骤二：</p>
<p>挖掘、收割、筛选，从“过往”收获经验。精心照料“此时此刻”的根茎，因为这正是旺盛生长的时期。有所计划与目标，着手种植“明天”。翻掘一下泥土，为孕育明天的梦想做好准备。</p>
<p>Step three:</p>
<p>Remember that grief is a natural predator, so learn to tolerate some damage. Protect your garden with daily prayers, for this will help you manage. Bury the criticism and complaining, for they are injurious pests. Sow the seed of love wherever you may go--for joy, love, and laughter are surely bound to grow. Although the thorns of life may be here to stay, just sprout a smile along the way...and be thankful for what you have today!</p>
<p>步骤三：</p>
<p>记住，“不幸”是天生的肉食动物，明白它们带来的伤害在所难免，你就会对不完美多一份理解和宽容。每天“祈祷”，保护你的花园，这有利于掌控。将“批评”与“埋怨”这些害虫掩埋起来。将“爱”的种子播散到你足迹所至的每个角落，“欢乐”、“爱”和“微笑”就会生机无限地发育成长。哪怕生命“荆棘”满途，也要在一旁种上微笑的芽苗……不管一切如何，为今天你所拥有的全部心存感激吧！</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ （分专题阅读）</p>
<p>☆ （精华博览版）</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ 特荐：</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
