<div>
<p>我想! 我做! 我得到! （双语有声美文）</p>
<p>There's a great song out there by Jimmy Cliff,one of reggae's top artists, that in six words summarizes just how you succeed in life: I want! I do! I get! These six words are a very powerful way of connecting what you want with what you will achieve.</p>
<p>世界顶尖的雷鬼音乐家吉米.克里夫(Jimmy Cliff)曾创作了这样一首了不起的歌曲，其歌名为《我想！我做！我得到！》。这六个字则把一个人怎样在一生中取的成功的经过进行了概括。这六个字是十分强有力的，它将“所想”与“所成”串在了一条线上。</p>
<p>First comes wanting something—a better life for yourself,your family, more money, a better job, whatever it is you dream about and long for. You desire it, you dream about it, you daydream about it, you yearn for it.</p>
<p>首先要做的就是要去想，想想让你和你的家人有更好的生活，赚更多的钱，找到更好的工作...无论这是你的梦想还是渴望，你想要得到这些，你梦想得到这些，你幻想会得到这些，并且你对此也充满了向往。</p>
<p>But that's not enough. Next and this the part too many people forget about—comes the doing. All of the wanting in the world is not going to move you one inch closer to what you want: you have to do.You have to find a better job, change jobs, take risks, write software, try new things, stop doing old things, go to college, work, act, do.The doing is the absolutely indispensable connection between what you want and what you get.</p>
<p>但光想还不够，下一步，往往也是大部分人忽视掉的这一步---付诸于行动。世上最遗憾的事莫过于梦想自己 不会向你的方向多靠近哪怕一英寸，因此你必须主动去接近梦想。于是你不得不去找一份更好的工作、经历跳槽、承担风险、编写软件、尝试新鲜事物、不再走老 路、去上学、去工作、去做事...从梦想到获得的路途中，行动是一座必经的桥梁。</p>
<p>Finally, if you keep doing what needs to be done, if you keep adjusting what you do to move you closer to what you want, you get. Maybe not easily, maybe not as quickly as movies and television portray,but it will come.</p>
<p>如果你始终在做需要做的事；如果你一直在调整你的方向，去做一些能让你更靠近梦想的事；那么最终，你就会圆梦。这或许不那么简单，这又或许没有电影电视中演得那么快，但这终究还是会成为现实。</p>
<p>One final philosophical note about these six words: notice that "I" is three of them? Not what others want, not what others say you are "supposed" or "should" do. What's more, no one is going to do it for you.</p>
<p>最后，让我们从哲学角度来审视一下这六个字:注意了，三个动作的主语都是 “我”。这是因为，梦想并不是他人的梦想；也不会有其他人对你说你“要去”或“该去”做什么。此外，也没有人会代替你去做什么。</p>
<p>You are the key to making these six words work.</p>
<p>因此，让这六个字发挥作用的人，只有你自己。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ （分专题阅读）</p>
<p>☆ （精华博览版）</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆ 特荐：</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
