<div>
<p>来自内心的礼物（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>According to legend, a young man while roaming the desert came across a spring of delicious crystal-clear water. The water was so sweet, he filled his leather canteen so he could bring some back to a tribal elder who had been his teacher.</p>
<p>据传说，一个年轻的男子在漫游沙漠途中看到一泉如水晶般清澈而可口的水。水的味道非常甜美，于是他灌满了他的皮水壶，这样就可以带一些回去，送给曾经是他老师的部落长老。</p>
<p>After a four-day journey he presented the water to the old man who took a deep drink, smiled warmly and thanked his student lavishly for the sweet water. The young man returned to his village with a happy heart.</p>
<p>经过四天的旅程，他把水呈献给老人。老人深饮一口，和蔼地笑了笑，并深切感激学生赠予他甜美的水。年轻人怀着愉快的心情回到了村庄。</p>
<p>Later, the teacher let another student taste the water. He spat it out, saying it was awful. It apparently had become stale because of the old leather container.</p>
<p>后来，老师让他的另一个学生品尝水。学生吐了出来，说水太难喝了。它显然已经因为陈旧的皮革容器而变得不再新鲜。</p>
<p>The student challenged his teacher: "Master, the water was foul. Why did you pretend to like it?"</p>
<p>学生质疑他的老师：“师父，水是臭的，你为什么要假装喜欢它？”</p>
<p>The teacher replied, "You only tasted the water. I tasted the gift. The water was simply the container for an act of loving-kindness and nothing could be sweeter."</p>
<p>老师回答说，“你只品尝了水的味道，我却是在品尝礼物的味道。水仅仅是装载善与爱之行为的容器，而没有什么东西比善与爱更甜美了。”</p>
<p>I think we understand this lesson best when we receive innocent gifts of love from young children. Whether it's a ceramic tray or a macaroni bracelet, the natural and proper response is appreciation and expressed thankfulness because we love the idea within the gift.</p>
<p>我认为当我们从天真的孩子们那里收到爱的礼物时，能够最透彻地明白这个道理。无论它是一个陶瓷托盘或通心粉手镯，我们自然而恰当的反应是欣赏，并表示感激，因为我们喜欢礼物所包含的心意。</p>
<p>Gratitude doesn't always come naturally. Unfortunately, most children and many adults value only the thing given rather than the feeling embodied in it. We should remind ourselves and teach our children about the beauty and purity of feelings and expressions of gratitude. After all, gifts from the heart are really gifts of the heart.</p>
<p>感恩并不总是自然而来的。不幸的是，大多数儿童和成人只看重被赠予的东西本身，而不是它体现的情谊。我们应该提醒自己，并教导我们的孩子，感情和对感激之情的表达是美丽而纯洁的。毕竟，发自内心给与的礼物才是真正的礼物。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
