<div>
<p>写给忠诚的狗狗们（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>A Tribute to the Dog</p>
<p>写给忠诚的狗</p>
<p>The best friend a man has in the world may turn against him and become his enemy. His son or daughter that he has reared with loving care may prove ungrateful. Those who are nearest and dearest to us, those whom we trust with our happiness and our good name may become traitors to their faith.</p>
<p>一个人在世上最好的朋友会和他反目，成为他的敌人。他悉心养育的儿女会不忠不孝。那些和我们最亲近的人，那些我们以幸福和美名信赖的人会背信弃义。</p>
<p>The money that a man has, he may lose. It flies away from him, perhaps when he needs it most. A man's reputation may be sacrificed in a moment of ill-considered action. The people who are prone to fall on their knees to do us honor when success is with us, may be the first to throw the stone of malice when failure settles its cloud upon our heads.</p>
<p>一个人拥有的金钱会失去，也许就在他最需要的时候。一个人的名誉会因瞬间的不当之举而丧失贻尽。那些当我们功成名就时跪拜向我们致敬的人也许是第一个在失败的阴云笼罩我们时对我们投石下井。</p>
<p>The one absolutely unselfish friend that man can have in this selfish world, the one that never deserts him, the one that never proves ungrateful or treacherous is his dog. A man's dog stands by him in prosperity and in poverty, in health and in sickness. He will sleep on the cold ground, where the wintry winds blow and the snow drives fiercely, if only he may be near his master's side. He will kiss the hand that has no food to offer.</p>
<p>在这个自私的世界里，一个人能有的最无私的，从不抛弃他，从不知恩不报，从不背信弃义的朋友是他的狗。无论富有或贫穷，无论健康或是患病，一个人的狗总佇立在主人身旁。如果能和主人在一起，它愿意睡在冰冷的地上，任凭寒风凛冽，朔雪飘零。它愿意亲吻没有食物奉送的手。</p>
<p>He will lick the wounds and sores that come in encounters with the roughness of the world. He guards the sleep of his pauper master as if he were a prince. When all other friends desert, he remains. When riches take wings, and reputation falls to pieces, he is as constant in his love as the sun in its journey through the heavens. If fortune drives the master forth, an outcast in the world, friendless and homeless, the faithful dog asks no higher privilege than that of accompanying him, to guard him against danger, to fight against his enemies.</p>
<p>它愿意舔抚艰难人世带来的创痕。它守卫着穷主人安睡如同守卫王子。当所有的朋友离去，它留驻。当财富不翼而飞，当名誉毁之贻尽，它仍然热爱着主人，如日当空，亘古不变。如果在命运驱使下，主人被世人抛弃，众叛亲离，无家可归，忠诚的狗仅仅要求能陪伴主人，守卫他免遭危险，去和他的敌人搏斗。</p>
<p>And when the last scene of all comes, and death takes his master in its embrace and his body is laid away in the cold ground, no matter if all other friends pursue their way, there by the graveside will the noble dog be found, his head between his paws, his eyes sad, but open in alert watchfulness, faithful and true even in death.</p>
<p>当最后的时刻来临，死神拥抱着主人，他的驱体掩埋在冰冷的黄土之下，任凭所有的朋友风流云散，就在墓地旁，你可以看见那高尚的狗，它的头伏在两爪之间，双眼神情悲伤，却警觉注视着，忠诚至死。</p>
</div>
