<div>
<p>做你想做的梦（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>There are moments in life when you miss someone so much that you just want to pick them from your dreams and hug them for real!</p>
<p>在一生有多少这样的时刻：我们对一个人朝思暮想，只想一把把他们从梦中拉出来，真切的拥抱一回！</p>
<p>When the door of happiness closes, another opens, but often times we look so long at the closed door that we don't see the one which has been opened for us.</p>
<p>一扇通往幸福的门关闭了，另一扇幸福之门打开了，可有多少次啊，我们徘徊在那扇关闭的门前，却忽略了那扇早已为我们开启的新的幸福之门。</p>
<p>Don't go for looks; they can deceive. Don't go for wealth; even that fades away. Go for someone who makes you smile because it takes only a smile to make a dark day seem bright. Find the one that makes your heart smile.</p>
<p>不要以貌取人，外貌可能会欺骗你；不要追逐财富，财富会消失的。去寻找那个让你笑口常开的人吧，一个微笑就可以使暗淡的日子豁然开朗。去追寻那个令你心灵愉悦的人吧！</p>
<p>Dream what you want to dream; go where you want to go; be what you want to be, because you have only one life and one chance to do all the things you want to do.</p>
<p>做你想做的梦，去你想去的地方，成为你想成为的人，因为你只有一次生命和一次机会去做你想做的事情。</p>
<p>May you have enough happiness to make you sweet, enough trials to make you strong, enough sorrow to keep you human, enough hope to make you happy.</p>
<p>愿幸福与你永伴，使你亲切可爱；愿你历经磨难，使你坚韧不拔；愿你痛彻心肺，使你通情达理，愿你充满希望，使你幸福快乐。</p>
<p>The happiest of people don't necessarily have the best of everything; they just make the most of everything that comes along their way.</p>
<p>世界上最幸福的人并不一定拥有最好的东西，他们只是最充分利用、珍惜了他们生命中的一切。</p>
<p>Love begins with a smile, grows with a kiss and ends with a tear.</p>
<p>爱始于微笑，育于亲吻，终于流泪。</p>
<p>The brightest future will always be based on a forgotten past, you can't go on well in life until you let go of your past failures and heartaches.</p>
<p>五彩缤纷的明天常常建立在对过去的遗忘之上。只有对过去的失败和伤痛不再耿耿于怀，生活才会变得更加美好。</p>
<p>When you were born, you were crying and everyone around you was smiling. Live your life so that when you die, you're the one who is smiling and everyone around you is crying.</p>
<p>当你呱呱落地、啼哭不已时，周围的人却笑逐颜开；要认真的生活，只有这样，当你走到生命的尽头时，你才会含笑而眠，而周围的人却痛哭不已。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
