<div>
<p>关于交友（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>Everyone needs friends,and if you fail to make friends,you should examine yourself and see if there is something wrong with your personality.</p>
<p>人人都需要朋友，若你在交朋友方面总是失败，就该反省自己，看是否你的个性有什么问题。</p>
<p>May be you have social faults such as snobbishness ,talkativeness and using slang  etc. which drive away your new acquaintances.Whatever your social faults may be,look at them honestly and make real effort to correct them.</p>
<p>或许你有些在社交上应该避讳的缺点，比如势力、饶舌、说脏话等，这些都会妨碍你结交新朋友。无论你有什么社交缺点，都该正视它们，尽力摒弃。</p>
<p>To be friendly you must feel friendly.Cheerfulness is the basis of friendliness.A cheerful person smiles.A smile is a magnet which draws people.Smile at someone and you are almost sure to get a smile in return.</p>
<p>要友善，你一定要给人友好的感觉：快乐是友善的基础。一个快乐的人总会面带微笑。微笑好似有吸引力的磁铁，你对别人微笑，你也会得到他微笑的回报。</p>
<p>A friendly person does his best to make a stranger feel at home,wherever he happens to be.Put yourself in the other fellow's place and make them feel welcome.</p>
<p>无论在哪里，友善之人都会让陌生人有居家般自在舒适的感觉，设身处地为陌生人考虑，让他有备受欢迎的感觉。</p>
<p>Try to remember names.It makes your new acquaintances feel happy when you call them by their names.It gives them the feeling that they have made an impression on you and that mean something to them because you remember them.</p>
<p>尽量记住人名。对新认识的朋友直呼其名会令他们很高兴，他们会觉得你对他有了一定的印象，这说明你记住了他们，这对他们很重要。</p>
<p>If you don't agree with other people on a certain matter,you should appear to be friendly.Don't argue,but discuss.You always lose friends if you argue too much.</p>
<p>若在某件事上你不能与别人达成一致意见，你该表现出友好。可以讨论，但不要争吵。争吵过甚会使你失去朋友。</p>
<p>A friendly person thinks of others,and doesn't insist on his own "rights".People who refuse to consider others have few friends.</p>
<p>友善之人常为他人考虑，不会为自己争取“权力”。不顾及别人的人，他的朋友寥寥无几。</p>
<p>Finally,don't treat people only according to their social positions.Really friendly people respect everyone at all times.</p>
<p>最后，切勿以社会地位论人。真正的友善之人往往尊重别人。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
