<div>
<p>认识你自己（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>Get a thorough understanding of oneself</p>
<p>认识你自己</p>
<p>In all one's lifetime it is oneself that one spends the most time being with or dealing with. But it is precisely  oneself that one has the least understanding of. When you are going upwards in life you tend to overestimate  yourself. When you are going downhill  you tend to underestimate  yourself. It's likely that you think it wise for yourself to know your place and stay aloof  from worldly wearing a mask of cowardice , behind which the flow of sap in your life will be retarded.


人生在世，和自己相处最多，打交道最多，但是人最不了解的也恰恰是自己。当你一帆风顺时，往往高估自己；不得志时，又往往低估自己。你可能认为安分守己、与世无争是明智之举，而实际上往往被怯懦的面具窒息了自己鲜活的生命。</p>
<p>To get a thorough understanding of oneself is to gain a correct view of oneself and be a sober realist—aware of both one's strength and shortage. You may look forward hopefully to the future but be sure not to expect too much, for ideals can never be fully realized. You may be courageous  to meet challenges but it should be clear to you where to direct your efforts. To get a thorough understanding of oneself needs self-appreciation . Whether you like yourself to a towering tree or a blade of grass, whether you think you are a high mountain or a small stone, you represent a state of nature that has its own reason of existence. If you earnestly admire yourself you'll have a real sense of self-appreciation, which will give you confidence. As soon as you gain full confidence in yourself you'll be enabled to fight and overcome any adversity.</p>
<p>彻悟自己，就是正确认识自己，做一个冷静的现实主义者，既知道自己的优势，也知道自己的不足。我们可以憧憬人生，但不要期望过高。因为在现实中，理想的实现总是会打折扣的。你可以勇敢地迎接挑战，但是必须清楚自己努力的方向。要彻悟自己就要欣赏自己。无论你是一棵参天大树，还是一棵无名小草，无论想要成为一座高山，还是一块石头，你都是一种天然，都有自己存在的理由。只要你认真地欣赏自己，你就会拥有一个真正的自我，你才会拥有信心。一旦拥有了信心你就能战胜任何灾难。</p>
<p>To get a thorough understanding of oneself also requires doing oneself a favor when it's needed. In time of anger, do yourself a favor by giving vent to it in a quiet place so that you won't be hurt by its flames; in time of sadness, do yourself a favor by sharing it with your friends so as to change a gloomy  mood into a cheerful one; in time of tiredness, do yourself a favor by getting a good sleep or taking some tonic. Show yourself loving concern about your health and daily life. Unless you know perfectly well when and how to do yourself a favor, you won't be confident and ready enough to resist the attack of illness.</p>
<p>要彻悟自己，就要善待自己。在气愤时善待自己，找个僻静之处宣泄一下，不要被那些无名之火伤身；忧伤时，要善待自己，找个好友倾诉一番，让低迷的情 绪高涨起来；劳累时，你要善待自己，睡个好觉或者吃点滋补品，对自己的健康和生活关心备至。唯有知道如何善待自己，你才会信心百倍，从容不迫地准备应对疾 病的侵袭。</p>
<p>To get a thorough understanding of oneself is to get a full control of one's life. Then one will find one's life full of color and flavor.</p>
<p>彻悟了自己，你才能把握自己的生命，你的生活才会丰富多彩、有滋有味！</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
