<div>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天（下）（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>The Scroll Marked Two  羊皮卷之二</p>
<p>And how will I act? I will love all manners of men for each has qualities to be admired even though they be hidden. With love I will tear down the wall fo suspicion and hate which they have built round their hearts and in its place will I build bridges so that my love may enter their souls.</p>
<p>我该怎样行动呢？我要爱每个人的言谈举止，因为人人都有值得钦佩的性格，虽然有时不易察觉。我要用爱摧毁困住人们心灵的高墙，那充满怀疑与仇恨的用墙。我要铺一座通向人们心灵的桥梁。</p>
<p>I will love the ambitious for they can inspire me! I will love the failures for they can teach me. I will love the kings for they are but human; I will love the meek for they are divine. I will love the rich for they are yet lonely; I will love the poor for they are so many. I will love the young for the faith they hold; I will love the old for the wisdom they share; I will love the beautiful for their eyes of sadness; I will love the ugly for their souls of peace.</p>
<p>我爱雄心勃勃的人，他们给我灵感。我爱失败的人，他们给我教训。我爱王侯将相，因为他们也是凡人。我爱谦恭之人，因为他们非凡。我爱富人，因为他们孤独。我爱穷人。因为穷人太多了。我爱少年，因为他们真诚。我爱长者，因为他们有智慧。我爱美丽的人，因为他们眼中流露着凄迷。我爱丑陋的人，因为他们有颗宁静的心。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>But how will I react to the actions of others? With love. For just as love is my weapon to open the hearts of men, love is also my shield to repulse the arrows of hate and the spears of anger. Adversity and discouragement will beat against my new shield and become as the softest of rains. My shield will protect me in the market place and sustain me when I am alone. It will uplift me in moments of despair yet it will calm me in time of exultation. It will become stronger and more protective with use until one day I will cast it aside and walk unencumbered among all manners of men and, when I do, my name will be raised high on the pyramid of life.</p>
<p>我该怎样回应他人的行为呢？用爱心。爱是我打开人们心扉的钥匙，也是我抵挡仇恨之箭与愤怒之矛的盾牌。爱使挫折变得如春雨般温和，它是我商场上的护身符：孤独时。给我支持；绝望时，使我振作；狂喜时，让我平静。这种爱心会一天天加强。越发又有保护力，直到有一天，我可以自然地面对芸芸众生，处之泰然。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用上身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>And how will I confront each whom I meet? In only one way. In silence and to myself I will address him and say I Love You. Though spoken in silence these words will shine in my eyes, unwrinkle my brow, bring a smile to my lips, and echo in my voice; and his heart will be opened. And who is there who will say nay to my goods when his heart feels my love?</p>
<p>我该怎样面对遇到的每一个人呢？只有一种办法，我要在心里默默地为他祝福。这无言的爱会闪现在我的眼神里，流露在我的眉宇间，让我嘴角挂上微笑，在我的声音里响起共鸣。在这无奈的爱意里，他的心扉问我敞开入他不再拒绝我推销的货物。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>And most of all I will love myself. For when I do I will zealously inspect all things which enter my body, my mind, my soul, and my heart. Never will I overindulge the requests of my flesh, rather I will cherish my body with cleanliness and moderation. Never will I allow my mind to be attracted to evil and despair, rather I will uplift it with the knowledge and wisdom of the ages. Never will I allow my soul to become complacent and satisfied, rather I will feed it with meditation and prayer. Never will I allow my heart to become small and bitter, rather I will share it and it will grow and warm the earth.</p>
<p>最主要的，我要爱自己。只有这样，我才会认真检查进入我的身体，思想，精神，头脑，灵魂，心怀的一切东西。我绝不放纵肉体的需求，我要用清洁与节制来珍惜我的身体。我绝不让头脑受到邪恶与绝望的引诱，我要用智慧和知识使之升华。我绝不让灵魂陷入自满的状态，我要用沉思和祈祷来滋润它。我绝不让心怀狭窄，我要与人分享，使它成长，温暖整个世界。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>Henceforth will I love all mankind. From this moment all hate is let from my veins for I have no time to hate, only time to love. From this moment I take the first step required to become a man among men. With love I will increase my sales a hundredfold and become a great salesman. If I have no other qualities I can succeed with love alone. Without it I will fail though I possess all the knowledge and skills of the world.</p>
<p>从今往后，我要爱所有的人。仇恨将从我的血管中流走。我没有时间去恨，只有时间去爱。现在，我迈出成为一个优秀的人的第一步。有了爱，我将成为伟大的推销员，即使才疏智短，也能以爱心获得成功；相反地，如果没有爱，即使博学多识，也终将失败。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love, and I will succeed.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>本文音频由作者曼狄诺原声朗读</p>
<p>作者简介：</p>
<p>奥格·曼狄诺是当今世界撰写自我帮助方面书籍的最流行最有灵感的作家。他著有14本书，销量超过3000万册，被译成18种语言。</p>
<p>成千上万的来自生活中各行各业的人们，都盛赞奥格·曼狄诺改变了他们的生活，从他的书中得到了神奇的力量。他的书充满智慧、灵感和爱心。他的著作包括：《世界上最伟大的奇迹》、《世界上最伟大的推销员》、《世界上最伟大的成功》等。</p>
</div>
