<div>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天 （上）（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>The Scroll Marked Two   羊皮卷之二</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>For this is the greatest secret of success in all ventures. Muscle can split a shield and even destroy life but only the unseen power of love can open the hearts of men and until I master this art I will remain no more than a peddler in the market place. I will make love my greatest weapon and none on whom I call can defend against its force.</p>
<p>因为，这是一切成功的最大秘密。强力能够劈开一块盾牌，甚至毁灭生命，但是只有爱才具有无与伦比的力量，使人们敞开心扉。在掌握了爱的艺术之前，我只算商场上的无名小卒。我要让爱成为我最大的武器，没有人能抵挡它的威力。</p>
<p>My reasoning they may counter; my speech they may distrust; my apparel they may disapprove; my face they may reject; and even my bargains may cause them suspicion; yet my love will melt all hearts liken to the sun whose rays soften the coldest clay.</p>
<p>我的理论，他们也许反对；我的言谈，他们也许怀疑；我的穿着，他们也许不赞成；我的长相，他们也许不喜欢；甚至我廉价出售的商品都可能使他们将信将疑，然而我的爱心一定能温暖他们，就像太阳的光芒能溶化冰冷的冻土。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>And how will I do this? Henceforth will I look on all things with love and I will be born again. I will love the sun for it warms my bones; yet I will love the rain for it cleanses my spirit. I will love the light for it shows me the way; yet I will love the darkness for it shows me the stars. I will welcome happiness for it enlarges my heart; yet I will endure sadness for it opens my soul. I will acknowledge rewards for they are my due; yet I will welcome obstacles for they are my challenge.</p>
<p>我该怎样做呢？从今往后，我对一切都要满收爱心，这样才能获得新生。我爱太阳，它温暖我的身体；我爱雨水。它洗净我的灵魂；我爱光明，它为我指引道路；我也爱黑夜，它让我看到星辰、我迎接快乐，它使我心胸开阔；我忍受悲伤，它升华我的灵魂；我接受报酬。因为我为此付出汗水；我不怕困难，因为它们给我挑战。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>And how will I speak? I will praise my enemies and they will become friends; I will encourage my friends and they will become brothers. Always will I dig for reasons to applaud; never will I scratch for excuses to gossip. When I am tempted to criticize I will bite on my tongue; when I am moved to praise I will shout from the roofs.</p>
<p>我该怎样说呢？我赞美敌人。敌人于是成为朋友；我鼓励朋友，朋友于是成为手足。我要常想理由赞美别人，绝不搬弄是非，道人长短。想要批评人时，咬住舌头，想要赞美人时，高声表达。</p>
<p>Is it not so that birds, the wind, the sea and all nature speak with the music of praise for their creator? Cannot I speak with the same music to his children? Henceforth will I remember this secret and it will change my life.</p>
<p>飞鸟，清风，海浪，自然界的万物不都在用美妙动听的歌声赞美造物主吗？我也要用同样的歌声赞美她的儿女。从今往后，我要记住这个秘密。它将改变我的生活。</p>
<p>I will greet this day with love in my heart.</p>
<p>我要用全身心的爱来迎接今天。</p>
<p>本文音频由作者曼狄诺原声朗读</p>
<p>作者简介：</p>
<p>奥格·曼狄诺是当今世界撰写自我帮助方面书籍的最流行最有灵感的作家。他著有14本书，销量超过3000万册，被译成18种语言。成千上万的来自生活中各行各业的人们，都盛赞奥格·曼狄诺改变了他们的生活，从他的书中得到了神奇的力量。他的书充满智慧、灵感和爱心。他的著作包括：《世界上最伟大的奇迹》、《世界上最伟大的推销员》、《世界上最伟大的成功》等。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
