<div>
<p>今天，我开始新的生活（下）（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>As a child I was slave to my impulses; now I am slave to my habits, as are all grown men. I have surrendered my free will to the years of accumulated habits and the past deeds of my life have already marked out a path which threatens to imprison my future. My actions are ruled by appetite, passion, prejudice, greed, love, fear, environment, habit, and the worst of these tyrants is habit. Therefore, if I must be a slave to habit let me be a slave to good habits. My bad habits must be destroyed and new furrows prepared for good seed.</p>
<p>小时候。我常会感情用事，长大成人了，我要用良好的习惯代替一时的冲动。我的自由意志屈服于多年养成的恶习，它们威胁着我的前途。我的行为受到品味、情感、偏见、欲望、爱、恐惧、环境和习惯的影响，其中最厉害的就是习惯。因此。如果我必须受习惯支配的话，那就让我受好习惯的支配。那些坏习惯必须戒除，我要在新的田地里播种好的种子。</p>
<p>I will form good habits and become their slave.</p>
<p>我要养成良好的习惯，全心全意去实行。</p>
<p>And how will I accomplish this difficult feat? Through these scrolls, it will be done, for each scroll contains  a principle which will drive a bad habit from my life and replace it with one which will bring me closer to success. For it is another of nature's laws that only a habit can subdue another habit. So, in order for these written words to perform their chosen task, I must discipline myself with the first of my new habits which is as follows:</p>
<p>这不是轻而易举的事情，要怎样才能做到呢，靠这些羊皮卷就能做到。因为每～卷里都写着一个原则，可以摒除-项坏习惯，换取一个好习惯，使人进步，走向成功。这也是自然法则之一，只有一种习惯才能抑制另一种习惯。所以，为了走好我选择的道路，我必须养成的第一个习惯：</p>
<p>I will read each scroll for thirty days in this prescribed manner, before I proceed to the next scroll.</p>
<p>每张羊皮卷用三十天的时间阅读，然后再进人下一卷。</p>
<p>First, I will read the words in silence when I arise. Then, I will read the words in silence after I have partaken of my midday meal. Last, I will read the words again just before I retire at day's end, and most important, on this occasion I will read the words aloud.</p>
<p>清晨即起，默默诵读；午饭之后，再次默读；夜晚睡前，高声朗读。</p>
<p>On the next day I will repeat this procedure, and I will continue in like manner for thirty days. Then, I will turn to the next scroll and repeat this procedure for another thirty days. I will continue in this manner until I have lived with each scroll for thirty days and my reading has become habit.</p>
<p>第二天的情形完全一样。这样重复三十天后，就可以打开下一卷了。每一卷都依照同样的方法读上三十天，久而久之，它们就成为一种习惯了。</p>
<p>And what will be accomplished with this habit? Herein lies the hidden secret of all man's accomplishments. As I repeat the words daily they will soon become a part of my active mind, but more important, they will also seep into my other mind, that mysterious source which never sleeps, which creates my dreams, and often makes me act in ways I do not comprehend.</p>
<p>这些习惯有什么好处呢？这里隐含着人类成功的秘诀。当我每天重复这些话的时候，它何成了我精神活动的一部分，更重要的是，它们渗入我的心灵。拥是个神秘的世界，永不静止，创造梦境，在不知不觉中影响我的行为。</p>
<p>As the words of these scrolls are consumed by my mysterious mind I will begin to awake, each morning, with a vitality I have never known before. My vigor will increase, my enthusiasm will rise, my desire to meet the world will overcome every fear I once knew at sunrise, and I will be happier than I ever believed it possible to be in this world of strife and sorrow.</p>
<p>当这些羊皮卷上的文字，被我奇妙的心灵完全吸收之后，我每天都会充满活力地醒来。我从来没有这样精力充沛过。我更有活力，更有热情，要向世界挑战的欲望克服了一切恐惧与不安。在这个充满争斗和悲伤的世界里，我竟然比以前更快活。</p>
<p>Eventually I will find myself reacting to all situations which confront me as I was commanded in the scrolls to react, and soon these actions and reactions will become easy to perform, for any act with practice becomes easy.</p>
<p>最后，我会发现自己有了应付一切情况的办法。不久，这些办法就能运用自如。因为，任何方法，只要多练习，就会变得简单易行。</p>
<p>Thus a new and good habit is born, for when an act becomes easy through constant repetition it becomes a pleasure to perform and if it is a pleasure to perform it is man's nature to perform it often. When I perform it often it becomes a habit and I become its slave and since it is a good habit this is my will.</p>
<p>经过多次重复，一种看似复杂的行为就变得轻而易举，实行起来，就会有无限的乐趣，有了乐趣，出于人之天性，我就更乐意常去实行。于是，一种好的习惯便诞生了。习惯成为自然。既是一种好的习惯，也就是我的意原。</p>
<p>Today I begin a new life.</p>
<p>今天，我天始新的生活。</p>
<p>And I make a solemn oath to myself that nothing will retard my new life's growth. I will lose not a day from these readings for that day cannot be retrieved nor can I substitute another for it. I must not, I will not, break this habit of daily reading from these scrolls and, in truth, the few moments spent each day on this new habit are but a small price to pay for the happiness and success that will be mine.</p>
<p>我郑重地发誓，绝不让任何事情妨碍我新生命的成长。在阅读这些羊卷的时候，我绝不浪费一天的时间，因为时光一去不返，失去的日子是无法弥补的。我也绝不打破每天阅读的习惯。事实上，每天在这些新习惯上花费少许时间，相对于可能获得的愉乐与成功而言，只是微不足道的代价。</p>
<p>As I read and re-read the words in the scrolls to follow, never will I allow the brevity of each scroll nor the simplicity of its words to cause me to treat the scroll's message lightly. Thousands of grapes are pressed to fill one jar with wine, and the grape skin and pulp are tossed to the birds. So it is with these grapes of wisdom from the ages. Much has been filtered and tossed to the wind. Only the pure truth lies distilled in the words to come. I will drink as instructed and spill not a drop. And the seed of success I will swallow.</p>
<p>当我阅读羊皮卷中的字句时，绝不能出为文字的精炼而忽视内容的深沉。一瓶葡萄美酒需要千百颗果子酿制而成，果皮和渣子抛给小鸟。葡萄的智慧代代相传，有些被过滤，有些被淘汰，随风飘逝。只有纯正的真理才是永恒的。它们就精炼在我要阅读的文字中。我要依照指示，绝不浪费，饮下成功的种子。</p>
<p>Today my old skin has become as dust. I will walk tall among men and they will know me not, for today I am a new man, with a new life.</p>
<p>今天，我的老茧化为尘埃。我在人群中昂首阔步，不会有人认出我来，因为我不再是过去的自己、我已拥有新的生命。</p>
<p>本文音频由作者曼狄诺原声朗读</p>
<p>作者简介：</p>
<p>奥格·曼狄诺是当今世界撰写自我帮助方面书籍的最流行最有灵感的作家。他著有14本书，销量超过3000万册，被译成18种语言。</p>
<p>成千上万的来自生活中各行各业的人们，都盛赞奥格·曼狄诺改变了他们的生活，从他的书中得到了神奇的力量。</p>
<p>他的书充满智慧、灵感和爱心。他的著作包括：《世界上最伟大的奇迹》、《世界上最伟大的推销员》、《世界上最伟大的成功》等。</p>
</div>
