<div>
<p>生而为赢（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>Born to win 生而为赢</p>
<p>Muriel James &amp; Dorothy Jongeward</p>
<p>Each human being is born as something new, something that never existed before. Each is born with the capacity to win at life. Each person has a unique way of seeing, hearing, touching, tasting and thinking. Each has his or her own unique potentials —capabilities and limitations. Each can be a significant, thinking, aware, and creative being — productive person, a winner.</p>
<p>人皆生而为新，为前所未有之存在；人皆生而能赢。人皆有其特立独行之方式去审视、聆听、触摸、品味及思考，因而都具备独特潜质——能力和局限。人皆能举足轻重，思虑明达，洞察秋毫，富有创意，成就功业。</p>
<p>The word “winner” and “loser” have many meanings. When we refer to a person as a winner, we do not mean one who makes someone else lose. To us, a winner is one who responds authentically by being credible, trustworthy, responsive, and genuine, both as an individual and as a member of a society.</p>
<p>“成者”与“败者”含义颇多。谈及成者我们并非指令他人失意之人。对我们而言，成者必为人守信，值得信赖，有求必应，态度诚恳，或为个人、或为社会一员皆能以真诚回应他人。</p>
<p>Winners do not dedicate their lives to a concept of what they imagine they should be; rather, they are themselves and as such do not use their energy putting on a performance, maintaining pretence and manipulating others. They are aware that there is a difference between being loving and acting loving, between being stupid and acting stupid, between being knowledgeable and acting knowledgeable. Winners do not need to hide behind a mask.</p>
<p>成者行事并不拘泥于某种信条，即便是他们认为应为其奉献一生的理念；而是本色行事，所以并不把精力用来表演，保持伪装或操控他人。他们明了爱与装爱、愚蠢与装傻、博学与卖弄之间迥然有别。成者无须藏于面具之后。</p>
<p>Winners are not afraid to do their own thinking and to use their own knowledge. They can separate facts from opinions and don't pretend to have all the answers. They listen to others, evaluate what they say, but come to their own conclusions. Although winners can admire and respect other people, they are not totally defined, demolished， bound, or awed by them.</p>
<p>成者敢于利用所学，独立思考，区分事实与观点，且并不佯装通晓所有答案。他们倾听、权衡他人意见，但能得出自己的结论。尽管他们尊重、敬佩他人，但并不为他人所局限、所推翻、所束缚，也不对他人敬若神灵。</p>
<p>Winners do not play “helpless”， nor do they play the blaming game. Instead, they assume responsibility for their own lives. They don't give others a false authority over them. Winners are their own bosses and know it.</p>
<p>成者既不佯装“无助”，亦不抱怨他人。相反，他们对人生总是独担责任，也不以权威姿态凌驾他人之上。他们主宰自己，而且能意识到这点。</p>
<p>A winner's timing is right. Winners respond appropriately to the situation. Their responses are related to the message sent and preserve the significance, worth, well-being, and dignity of the people involved. Winners know that for everything there is a season and for every activity a time.</p>
<p>成者善于审时度势，随机应变。他们对所接受的信息做出回应，维护当事人的利益、康乐和尊严。成者深知成一事要看好时节，行一事要把握时机。</p>
<p>Although winners can freely enjoy themselves, they can also postpone enjoyment, can discipline themselves in the present to enhance their enjoyment in the future. Winners are not afraid to go after what he wants, but they do so in proper ways. Winners do not get their security by controlling others. They do not set themselves up to lose.</p>
<p>尽管成者可以自由享乐，但他更知如何推迟享乐，适时自律，以期将来乐趣更盛。成者并不忌惮追求所想，但取之有道，也并不靠控制他人而获取安然之感。他们总是使自己立于不败。</p>
<p>A winner cares about the world and its peoples. A winner is not isolated from the general problems of society, but is concerned, compassionate， and committed to improving the quality of life. Even in the face of national and international adversity, a winner's self-image is not one of a powerless individual. A winner works to make the world a better place.</p>
<p>成者心忧天下，并不孤立于尘世弊病之外，而是置身事内，满腔热忱，致力于改善民生。即使面对民族、国家之危亡，成者亦非无力回天之个体。他总是努力令世界更好。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
