<div>
<p>只为今天（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>Just for today 只为今天</p>
<p>By Dale Carnegie 戴尔 卡耐基</p>
<p>Just for today I will try to live through this day only and not tackle my whole life problem at once. I can do something for twelve hours that would appall me if I had to keep it up for a lifetime.</p>
<p>只为今天，我将尽力只度过今天而不立刻去解决终身的问题。对一件令我沮丧而又必须坚持一辈子的事，我只能坚持十二个小时。</p>
<p>Just for today I will be happy. This assumes to be true what Abraham Lincoln said，that “Most folks are as happy as they make up their minds to be.”</p>
<p>只为今天，我会很快乐。亚伯拉罕-林肯说过，“大多数人都是决定想怎么高兴就怎么高兴。”这已经被认为是真理。</p>
<p>Just for today I will adjust myself to what is, and not try to adjust everything to my own desires. I will take my “luck” as it comes.</p>
<p>只为今天，我会做自我调整适应事物本来的面目，而不是想方设法使每一件事满足自己的欲望。当机会来临的时候我会抓住它。</p>
<p>Just for today I will try to strengthen my mind. I will study. I will learn something useful. I will not be a mental loafer. I will read something that requires effort, thought and concentration.</p>
<p>只为今天，我会尽力心强志坚。我会学习，学一些有用的东西。我不会做一个精神上的流浪汉。我会读一些需要努力、思考和注意力集中的东西。</p>
<p>Just for today I will exercise my soul in three ways. I will do somebody a good turn and not get found out: If anybody knows of it, it will not count. I will do at least two things I don't want to do—just for exercise. I will not show anyone that my feelings are hurt: they may be hurt, but today I will not show it.</p>
<p>只为今天，我会用三种方法来磨炼我的灵魂。我会做对某人有利的事但不能被发现，若有人发现了就不算数。我将会做至少两件我不愿做的事情——只为了磨练。我不会让任何人感到我的感情受到了伤害：它们可能受到了伤害，但今天我不想表现出来。</p>
<p>Just for today I will be agreeable. I will look as well as I can, dress becomingly, talk low, act courteously, criticize not one bit，and try not to improve or regulate anybody but myself.</p>
<p>只为今天，我会过得很惬意。看起来我达到了最佳状态，穿着得体、讲话谦虚、行为礼貌、一点不吹毛求疵，尽量改进和调节自己而不是别人。</p>
<p>Just for today I will have a program, I may not follow it exactly, but I will have it. I will save myself from two pests: hurry and indecision.</p>
<p>只为今天，我会制定一个计划，我也许不会严格地遵守它，但我一定要有计划。我会避免两种错误：仓促行事和优柔寡断。</p>
<p>Just for today I will have a quiet half hour all by myself and relax. During this half hour, sometime, I will try to get a better perspective of my life.</p>
<p>只为今天，我将会独自静静地呆上半小时放松。在这半小时里，某个时刻，我会日后对我的生活有个更好的看法。</p>
<p>Just for today I will be unafraid. Especially I will not be afraid to enjoy what is beautiful，and to believe that as I give to the world, so the world will give to me.</p>
<p>只为今天，我将不再害怕。尤其我不会再害怕享受美丽的事物，并且相信我给予世界的，世界也会给予我。</p>
<p>作者简介：</p>
<p>戴尔·卡耐基（Dale Carnegie，1888－1955年)，被誉为是20世纪最伟大的心灵导师。</p>
<p>卡耐基是美国著名的企业家、教育家和演讲口才艺术家，被誉为“成人教育之父”。早在20世纪上半叶，当经济不景气、不平等、战争等恶魔正在磨灭人类追求美好生活的心灵时，卡耐基先生以他对人性的洞见，利用大量普通人不断努力取得成功的故事，通过他的演讲和著作唤起无数陷入迷惘者的斗志，激励他们取得辉煌的成功。</p>
</div>
