<div>
<p>1℃的爱情（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>1℃ love</p>
<p>1℃的爱情</p>
<p>In a cold winter, a couple had to move out from the luxury villa because of bankruptcy. The husband worked day and night to support the family but with no care of his wife. So she thought, “he doesn't love me any more, he just cares his business…not me”。</p>
<p>一个寒冷的冬天，一对夫妇因为破产，所以不得不从豪宅里搬出。丈夫每天辛勤工作以维持家庭开支，但很少顾及到妻子。于是，妻子暗自想道：“他不再爱我了，他只在乎他的事业，而不是我。”</p>
<p>One day, she began to take a bath, he stopped her at the door, “Let me take it first, okay?”</p>
<p>一天，妻子准备洗澡，可丈夫叫住了她，“让我先洗吧。”</p>
<p>“Why not let me shower first,” she asked. “I was tired, sweetie, you take it later, okay?” She was totally depressed.</p>
<p>“为什么不让我先洗呢？”“亲爱的，因为我很累，你之后再洗吧？”妻子为此很不开心。</p>
<p>On a morose day, she found nothing to do and turned on his computer, a few words blurred her eyes…it was his diary:</p>
<p>一天，妻子无所事事，郁郁寡欢，于是打开了丈夫的电脑。上面的几行字让她的眼睛湿润了，那是他的日记。</p>
<p>Today, I was quite sad, she asked me why I was always taking the bath first, and I said to her, I was exhausted. She was unhappy, in her mind, I treated her not as well as usual, but how can I do? I was not as rich as before! We moved to the small apartment, there was only a shower in the bathroom, it was so cold to take a shower in such a freezing winter. But I found that if one person took the shower first, the room could get a little warm, so every time I rushed to the bathroom first. I was thinking that, when she took the shower, the room would get warmer, at least 1℃， 2℃ or 3℃。</p>
<p>今天，我很不开心，因为她问我为什么总是我先洗澡，而我对她说，因为我太累了，想先洗。她肯定不高兴了，觉得我对她不像以前那么好了。但是我该怎么做呢？我不像以前那么有钱呀！我们搬到了一个小公寓，只有一个洗澡间，在这样的冬天洗澡真是冻死人了。但我发现，如果一个人先洗的话，浴室就会暖和的，所以每次我都第一个冲进浴室。我想，等她进去浴室时，至少暖和一两度吧。</p>
<p>Now I can't give her comfortable life, bring her the luxury restaurant, buy expensive dresses for her, but at least, I can give her 1℃ love.</p>
<p>现在，我不能给她舒适的生活，带她去高级餐厅，给她买漂亮的衣服，但至少我还能给她1℃的爱情。</p>
<p>【特别推荐】</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
<p>☆</p>
</div>
