<div>
<p>双语美文：成功的七大要素（双语有声美文）</p>
<p>I don’t believe that there is any one recipe for success. Instead, I believe success is the result of a combination of a lot of different factors - and not all of them are needed for success. The more factors you have on your side, the more likely you are to succeed, and positive attitude is just one of those factors. Here are seven additional factors that are also important.</p>
<p>我不认为成功有任何的秘诀.相反，我相信成功是多种因素结合的结果，其中有些因素对于成功是不必要的。拥有越多对你有利的因素，你就越有可能成功，积极的态度只是其中之一。以下7个因素也很重要。</p>
<p>Knowledge A strong body of knowledge about the area in which you wish to succeed is often one of the key building blocks of success. You can build this by pushing yourself - read and try out the foundational materials and push yourself into challenging areas to build your knowledge.</p>
<p>知识。对你希望涉足的领域有充足的知识储备往往是成功的关键基石。你可以通过阅读或尝试基础性的东西使自己前进；或者，敦促自己进入有挑战性的领域以建立自己的知识库。</p>
<p>Natural talent Some people are born with a predisposition to succeed in certain areas. Find this out for yourself by trying a lot of different activities and seeing what comes easy to you. The things you do with little or no effort that genuinely impress others are likely very near your natural talent, and natural talent combined with a lot of hard work leads to greatness.</p>
<p>天赋。有些人天生就具有在某些领域取得成功的资质。通过尝试不同的活动，看看哪些更适合自己，找出适合自己的发展领域。那些你花费很少精力、不费吹灰之力去做能真正打动别人的事物，可能就是你的天赋所在。天赋加上勤奋就会成功。</p>
<p>Clear goals and planning Much like a trip, it’s a lot easier to get where you want to go if you know where you’re going and spend the time to plan the route you’ll take to get there. Think about what your definition of success exactly is, then identify some of the things that need to be done to help you move towards it.</p>
<p>明确目标和计划。就像旅行一样，如果你知道自己的目的地并花时间去计划路线的话，达到目的地会很容易。想想你对成功确切的定义是什么，然后明确一下那些能助你朝目标迈进的事情，并完成它们。</p>
<p>Passion An intense, burning desire to dig deep into a particular area is often a sign that you’ll find success there. Much as with your natural talent, the way to find your passion is to touch on a lot of different areas and see what resonates for you.</p>
<p>激情。想要深入某一特定领域的强烈愿望通常是你将在这一领域有所建树的迹象。想象寻找自己的天赋所在一样，找到自己的兴趣所在的方式也是通过涉足不同的领域，看哪些能和自己长生共鸣。</p>
<p>Focus/consistent effort Hard work is another key to finding success. You don’t become a champion without practicing every day. If you want to succeed in a certain area, work hard in that area and go beyond what others are doing - deliberate practice is one big key.</p>
<p>专注、始终如一的努力。努力是成功的另一关键。没有每天的训练不可能成为冠军。如果想在某一领域成功，那就在这一领域努力吧，而且要比其他人更努力---游刃有余也是一个重要环节。</p>
<p>Luck/opportunity Luck and opportunity also play an important role in success - sometimes things just click due to forces outside your control. You can improve your luck by making as many strong personal contacts as you can and sharing what you have to increase their “luck” and “opportunities.”</p>
<p>运气、机会。运气和机会也发挥了重要作用—有时事情受你控制之外的外力影响只会昙花一现。你可以尽可能多地建立人际关系，与他们分享自己所得，这可提升他人的运气和机会，通过这些想法，你也会改善自己的运气。</p>
<p>Cooperation/support Along with luck comes cooperation - the fact that others are working in small ways to help you succeed rather than hinder you. A spouse telling you that you can do this is going to go a lot further than a spouse telling you you’ll never make it.</p>
<p>合作、支持。伴随着好运一起来的是合作---事实在于，别人是通过不显著的方式助你成功，而并没有阻碍你。鼓励远比打击更能使人进步。</p>
</div>
